{
  "q1": [
    {
      "question": "An independence movement in this modern-day country started when Carlos Cespedes freed all his slaves and proclaimed the October 10th Manifesto. This country’s anthem ”La Bayamesa” was composed during the Ten Years War. Valeriano Weyler was called “the Butcher” after his brutal suppression of rebels in this modern-day country. Jos´e Mart´ı was killed fighting for independence from Spain for, for ten points, what Caribbean island nation with its capital at Havana?",
      "answer": "Republic of Cuba"
    },
    {
      "question": "ThisleaderestablishedanationalinquiryintothestatusofMMIWinhiscountry.Thisprimeminister, who ran on the slogan “Real Change,” has been accused by Jody Wilson-Raybould of obstruction of justice. This man expelled Jane Philpott from his party in 2019 over the SNC-Lavalin scandal. This man responded “because it’s 2015” when asked why gender parity was important to his cabinet. For 10 points, name this current Prime Minister of Canada.",
      "answer": "Justin Trudeau"
    },
    {
      "question": "A series of lawsuits brought by this man’s heirs were known as his namesake pleitos. This man was granted royal titles and a tenth of the riches he discovered in the Capitulations of Santa Fe. This man’s expedition was chronicled in The Life of the Admiral. The Bay of Arrows was named by this man after he was attacked by the Ciguayos people in the first of his voyages to Hispaniola. Ferdinand and Isabella commissioned the voyages of, for ten points, what navigator who is often credited with “discovering” America?",
      "answer": "Christopher Columbus"
    },
    {
      "question": "After Offa of Mercia offered a marriage between this man’s daughter Bertha and Ecgfrith, this man banned English ships from his ports. This man’s brother Carloman allied against him with the Lombard King Desiderius. Lupo II of Gascony may have helped ambush his men at the Roncevaux Pass, in which his chronicler Einhard noted every soldier was killed. This man’s sons divided his empire after he died in the Treaty of Verdun. The son of Pepin the Short, for ten points, name this first Holy Roman Emperor.",
      "answer": [
        "Charlemagne Or Charles the Great,",
        "Carolus Magnus"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "The book The Destiny of The Mother Church is controversial in this sect for comparing this sect’s founder to Jesus Christ. Mark Twain wrote a book about this sect in which he breaks 102 bones and isn’t treated. Members of this sect believe that they can be cursed by “malicious animal magnetism” and collect books in their “reading rooms.” For ten points, name this sect, founded by Mary Baker Eddy, which publishes a namesake “Monitor” and believes sickness is an illusion curable by prayer.",
      "answer": "Christian Science"
    },
    {
      "question": "One leader from this family was targeted by the Yanan Faction in the “Second Arduous March.” Another member of this family was suspected of ordering the 1983 Rangoon bombing as part of his songun, or military-first, policy. Economic reforms under a leader from this family included the opening of the Kaesong Industrial Park, a reversal of his predecessor’s juche ideology. For ten points, name this family which has ruled North Korea since its founding, whose members included Il-Sung and Jong-il.",
      "answer": "Kim family"
    },
    {
      "question": "The SSNIP test checks for violations of this type of legislation. “Tying” claims are often made citing this type of legislation. The case of Flood v. Kuhn upheld the exception granted to Major League Baseball from this type of legislation. The E.C. Knight ruling weakened a law of this type that had been passed in 1890. For ten points, name this type of law that guarantees fair competition as a benefit to consumers, two of which are named for Clayton and Sherman.",
      "answer": "antitrust acts"
    },
    {
      "question": "This man controversially placed bishop Aloysius Stepinac under house arrest where he died. This man secured power after executing Draza Mihailovic, the leader of the Chetnik Movement, for collaborating with the Ustase [oo-sta-shuh]. During the Informbiro period, this man’s disagreements with Joseph Stalin led his country to be expelled from Cominform. The Non-Aligned Movement was co-founded by this Partisan leader. For ten points, identify this marshal who led communist Yugoslavia.",
      "answer": "Josip Broz Tito"
    },
    {
      "question": "James P. Coleman established this state’s “Sovereignty Commission” which was meant to support racial segregation. A professor from this state, Clennon Washington King Jr., was labeled the “Black Don Quixote” and was the first African-American to run for President. The murder of three CORE activists in this state’s Neshoba county prompted a federal investigation labeled “this state” Burning. Ross Barnett opposed the Freedom Summer movement in this state which sought to register African-Americans to vote. For ten points, name this Southern state whose flagship “Ole” university was integrated by James Meredith.",
      "answer": "Mississippi"
    },
    {
      "question": "This artist adopted the Precisionist style to paint a series of skyscrapers, including “Radiator Building – Night.” In 1939, this artist begrudgingly painted a pineapple after Dole funded a trip to Hawaii to see one. This artist created paintings titled “White Place” and “Black Place” during a stay in Taos, New Mexico, and appears in the photos of her husband, Alfred Stieglitz. For 10 points, name this artist, famous for her paintings of flowers and cow skulls.",
      "answer": "Georgia O’Keeffe"
    }
  ],
  "q2": [
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "Pierre Pelletier and Joseph Caventou isolated and named the active agent of one cure for this disease over 100 years after that cure was first introduced to Europe by the Jesuits from the Andes. Because this disease’s merozoites infect and travel via red blood cells, sickle cell anemia provides moderate resistance against, for ten points, what disease which is increasingly resistant to quinine and is caused by Plasmodium parasites carried by Anopholes mosquitoes?",
        "answer": "malaria"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Tu Youyou was awarded the Nobel Prize in Medicine for her discovery of what drug, whose derivates are currently the most effective antimalarial treatment?",
        "answer": "artemisinin"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "The first holder of this position wrote down verses from Sophocles’ Ajax before jumping out a window at the National Naval Medical Center. Another holder of this position, James Schlesinger, was dismissed in part due to lying about carrying out tactical strikes during the Mayaguez incident. Robert McNamara held this position for over 2,000 days, allowing him to oversee the majority of the Vietnam War. The National Security Act of 1947 merged the Navy and War Departments to create, for ten points, what Cabinet position that oversees the armed forces?",
        "answer": [
          "Secretary of Defense",
          "SecDef"
        ]
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "James Schlesinger was removed as Secretary of Defense by this President who assumed the office after his predecesor resigned in 1974.",
        "answer": "Gerald Ford"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "A general who failed to send his troops in this campaign’s Battle of Simancas was crucified at an Al-Qasr. Including the Crusade of Barbastro, this effort began after Bishop Oppas failed to broker an accord, thus leading Munuza’s forces to be defeated by Pelagius following the Battle of Covadonga. Leading to the repopulation of the Douro Basin and the Ebro valley, this effort included Ferdinand III of Castile’s victory at Seville. For ten points, name this effort by Christian forces to recapture what is now Portugal and Spain.",
        "answer": "The Reconquista"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "The Reconquista ended when this final independent city fell to Catholic forces in 1492. It was last ruled by Muhammad XII and earlier, its Sultan Yusuf I supported a Marinid Invasion at the Battle of R´ıo Salado.",
        "answer": "Granada"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "Krzysztof Penderecki’s second symphony extensively quotes one of these pieces. Movements such as “Wolcum Yole” and “This Little Babe” appear in a Benjamin Britten work titled for a “Ceremony” of these pieces. Franz Gruber composed the music for one of these pieces with words by Joseph Mohr. Another one of these pieces includes the lyric “join the triumph of the skies”. For ten points, name these pieces written for a certain holiday such as “Silent Night”.",
        "answer": [
          "Christmas carols",
          "no¨el,"
        ]
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "The melody of “Hark! The Herald Angels Sing” comes from this composer’s Gutenberg Cantata. He also composed the Reformation and Scottish Symphonies.",
        "answer": "Felix Mendelssohn"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This leader renamed the Westbrook House and implemented the Reconstruction and Development Programme. This founder of “The Elders” gave a speech which was inspired by Castro’s “History Will Absolve Me” speech. This man successfully negotiated with F.W De Klerk and oversaw the formation of the Truth and Reconciliation Committee. After the Rivonia Trial, this opponent of apartheid was imprisoned for years on Robben Island. For ten points, name the first black President of South Africa.",
        "answer": "Nelson Mandela"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Nelson Mandela founded the group Umkhonto we Sizwe after this March 1960 massacre where 249 people protesting pass laws were shot at a police station.",
        "answer": "Sharpeville Massacre"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "Franklin Pierce asked this man, along with John Mason and Pierre Soule, to draft the Ostend Manifesto. This man’s Secretary of War, John Floyd, was accused of moving hundreds of thousands of rifles to different armories in the United States. Lewis Cass resigned as this man’s Secretary of State due to the perceived failure of this man to mobilize federal troops in response to Southern secession talk. For ten points, name this only bachelor President who is often criticized for failing to prevent the Civil War.",
        "answer": "James Buchanan"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Buchanan defeated this first Republican Party candidate for president in 1856. This California explorer ruled autocratically over the Department of the West in 1861.",
        "answer": "John C. Fremont"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "Father Henry Garnet was unable to warn this event’s target because Catholic law forbade him from revealing confessionals. This event’s planners attempted to fight off arrest during a gun battle at Holbeche House. An anonymous letter to Lord Monteagle revealed the details of this event. Robert Catesby was arrested for planning this event, in which 36 barrels of explosives were found in the House of Lords. For ten points, identify this event where Guy Fawkes tried to blow up Parliament.",
        "answer": "Gunpowder Plot"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Catesby and Fawkes were dissident Catholics disappointed that this Protestant king, who united the Scottish and English crowns, was less tolerant of Catholics than they had hoped.",
        "answer": [
          "James I",
          "James VI of Scotland"
        ]
      }
    }
  ],
  "q3": [
    {
      "category": "American Women’s Suffrage",
      "prompt": "Name the...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "Constitutional amendment, adopted in 1920, that guaranteed women the right to vote.",
          "answer": "19th Amendment to the US Constitution"
        },
        {
          "question": "US President who was called “Kaiser” during protests outside the White House in 1917.",
          "answer": "Woodrow Wilson"
        },
        {
          "question": "Future US state where women’s suffrage was overturned by an 1887 anti-polygamy act targeting Mormons.",
          "answer": "Utah Territory"
        },
        {
          "question": "Future US state that, in 1869, was first to grant women the right to vote.",
          "answer": "Wyoming"
        },
        {
          "question": "Group of protesters who were attacked in the Night of Terror, a group named for their quiet approach to picketing the White House.",
          "answer": "Silent Sentinels"
        },
        {
          "question": "19th century suffragette who co-founded the AWSA and controversially kept her maiden name after marrying Henry Blackwell.",
          "answer": "Lucy Stone"
        },
        {
          "question": "Feminist group led by Frances Willard that promoted suffrage but primarily focused on anti-alcohol efforts.",
          "answer": "Woman’s Christian Temperance Union or WCTU"
        },
        {
          "question": "Controversial book, produced by a committee led by Elizabeth Cady Stanton, that attacked the religious concept of female subservience; it led to Stanton’s fall from grace within the suffrage movement.",
          "answer": "The Woman’s Bible do not"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "category": "Hundred Years’ War",
      "prompt": "Name the...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "Two main combatant countries in the war, separated by a European channel.",
          "answer": [
            "England and France",
            "in either order"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "1415 battle, a victory for Henry V on Saint Crispin’s Day.",
          "answer": "Battle of Agincourt"
        },
        {
          "question": "Region, named for a city across that channel from the Cliffs of Dover, where a pale was established after the Battle of Crecy.",
          "answer": "Calais"
        },
        {
          "question": "Dynastic house whose first king was Philip VI and which fought the Plantagenets in the war.",
          "answer": "House of Valois"
        },
        {
          "question": "Region led by Philip the Bold that often switched sides during the war.",
          "answer": "Burgundy"
        },
        {
          "question": "1420 treaty that gave Henry V inheritance of the enemy’s crown and Catherine ‘s hand in marriage.",
          "answer": "Treaty of Troyes"
        },
        {
          "question": "“Beloved” king who went insane during the war and signed the aforementioned treaty.",
          "answer": "Charles VI"
        },
        {
          "question": "Leader of an abortive Welsh rebellion in 1400 during the Hundred Years’ War.",
          "answer": "Owen Glendower or Owain Glyndwr"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "category": "Arab Spring",
      "prompt": "Name the...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "Country in which Hosni Mubarak was overthrown in 2011.",
          "answer": "Egypt"
        },
        {
          "question": "Square in that country’s capital where many demonstrations took place.",
          "answer": "Tahrir Square"
        },
        {
          "question": "Country where protests in Damascus turned into an ongoing civil war.",
          "answer": "Syria"
        },
        {
          "question": "Libyan city where Ansar al-Sharia attacked a US consulate in 2012.",
          "answer": "Benghazi"
        },
        {
          "question": "Country where the Arab Spring began in 2010 with the immolation of a street vendor.",
          "answer": "Tunisia"
        },
        {
          "question": "Leader of that country, the only leader to be ousted and ultimately replaced with a lasting democratic system.",
          "answer": "Zine El Abidine Ben Ali"
        },
        {
          "question": "Name of that street vendor whose protest began the movement.",
          "answer": "Mohamed Bouazizi"
        },
        {
          "question": "Mubarak-aligned politician who narrowly lost to Mohammed Morsi in a controversial 2012 election.",
          "answer": "Ahmed Shafik"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  "q4": [
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) Abraham Lincoln asked Charlotte Cushman to see her play this character from his favorite Shakspearian play, which had been her first dramatic role. In Act 1 Scene 7, this character reassures another “screw your (20 pts)",
        "courage to the sticking-place, and we’ll not fail.” While sleepwalking, this character cries “Yet who would have thought the old man to have had so much (10 pts)",
        "blood in him” while trying to clean the “damned spot” from her hands. For ten points, name this Shakespearean character who helped her husband murder the Scottish King Duncan. ANSWER:Lady Macbeth(acceptdescriptionsof Macbeth’s wife;donotprompton“Macbeth”alone) (2) This battle was preceded by the fall of Fort St. John which nearly resulted in the capture of Guy Carleton. Daniel Morgan was one of over 300 soldiers to be captured in this battle. (+) Benedict Arnold was shot in the leg during this battle, hours after leading troops across the (*) Plains of Abraham. In the winding hours of this battle, Aaron Burr attempted to recover the body of Richard Montgomery who had, days prior, captured Montreal. For ten points, name this crushing 1775 defeat which ended the American invasion of Canada."
      ],
      "answer": "Battle of Quebec"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) Dead Horse Camp was established by an explorer traveling on this river. One explorer of this river was believed to be immortal and during an eclipse, was given gifts by the (20 pts)",
        "Aisuari people to not extinguish the sun. Samuel Fritz helped preach to the Cambeba people who lived along this river. In his search for the (10 pts)",
        "“Lost City of Z”, Percy Fawcett travelled down this river into the Mato Grosso region. Tapuya women fighting alongside men helped give this river its name. For ten points, name this river that crosses a massive rainforest in Brazil."
      ],
      "answer": "Amazon River"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) In 1663, a Great Fire destroyed most of this city, including a shrine to Mazu. Portuguese Jesuits ruled this city for seven years after it was ceded to them by (20 pts)",
        "Dom Bartolomeu. A Dutch trading post on the island of Dejima in this city was the only location open to (10 pts)",
        "Westerners during the Edo Period. This city was targeted for one attack after Henry Stimson removed his honeymoon destination, Kyoto, from a target list. The bomber Bockscar dropped Fat Man on, for ten points, what second Japanese city to be hit by an atomic bomb, three days after Hiroshima?"
      ],
      "answer": "Nagasaki"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) In one work, Pierre-Joseph Proudhon asked what is this concept, only to respond that it is theft. In Discourse on Inequality, Rousseau claimed that the first person to create this concept “and [find] people simple enough to believe him” was the founder of (20 pts)",
        "civil society. That work argues against the Second Treatise on Government, where Locke argued that this concept was justified by a person’s (10 pts)",
        "labor in creating value and paired the right to this concept with the rights to life and liberty. For ten points, name this concept, where a person privately owns something."
      ],
      "answer": "property"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) In this state, Mary McLeod Bethune, inspired by the work of Lucy Laney in Georgia, opened a school for African-American girls. The president of this state’s branch of the NAACP, Harry (20 pts)",
        "Moore, was killed in a 1951 bombing orchestrated by the KKK. A white mob in this state killed Julius Perry for allegedly sheltering Mose Norman as part of the Ocoee massacre. In 1923, the entire town of (10 pts)",
        "Rosewood was burned to the ground in this state as part of rising racial tensions. For ten points, name this Southern state where lynchings often took place in Orlando."
      ],
      "answer": "Florida"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This battle, which took place at the same location as the later Battle of Preveza, occurred after its loser was turned back at Corcyra and wintered in the (20 pts)",
        "Ambracian Gulf. The losing side of this battle suffered the defection of Quintus Dellius and had lost many rowers to (10 pts)",
        "malaria. The losing side’s rear forces in this battle were led by a queen who fled without fighting, leading to a victory for Marcus Vipsanius Agrippa. Mark Antony and Cleopatra fled to Egypt and later committed suicide after, for ten points, what decisive 31 BC naval victory for Octavian?"
      ],
      "answer": "Battle of Actium"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) A rat-infested plaster elephant occupied the site of this building after debate about whether it should be commemorated. The Comte d’Artois and the Duchess de Polignac fled after one event at this building, which overlooked the (20 pts)",
        "Faubourg Saint-Antoine. The Marquis de Sade was transferred from this building 10 days before an event at this building that followed the capture of arms at the (10 pts)",
        "Invalides. Bertrand de Launay’s head was raised on a pike by the “vanquishers” of this building. For ten points, name this Parisian fortress which was captured on July 14th, 1789."
      ],
      "answer": "The Bastille"
    }
  ]
}